Taylor McClerin

mcclerinette@gmail.com



FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER · LinkedIn · GitHub · Site · Master's Thesis

PROFILE: Full stack software engineer with a decade of leadership experience in public, private, and non-profit organizations. I develop software to bridge sectors and foster better outcomes for stakeholders.

LANGUAGES:

JavaScript(JS), TypeScript(TS), Python, SQL, HTML, CSS,

FRAMEWORKS:

Node.js, Sequelize, SQLAlchemy, Express, Flask, Django, Prisma, React, React-redux, , Tailwind-CSS

TOOLS:

Github, Amazon Web Services(AWS), Docker

Statistical Product and Service Solutions (SPSS), Geographical Information Systems (GIS), Project coordination and management, Microsoft Office, French (advanced fluency) & Spanish (novice fluency)

RECENT EMPLOYMENT

GAZELLE ECOSOLUTIONS · Full-stack Software Engineer · Austin, TX

Oct 2023 - Present

- Led front end development of new software launch (react, react-redux, tailwind-CSS) with Google Earth Engine (GEE) interface and components.
- Developed and tested UI/UX-centered components in react and developed Stories and documentation
- Optimized software interfacing with GEE by querying Landsat data to return remote sensing calculations using python
- Managed product and led full stack development (react, react-redux, tailwind-CSS, Django, Prisma) to provide project developers a platform to input data for VCS VM0042, Methodology for Improved Agricultural Land Management
- Researched GEE optimization and presented conclusions internally
- Presented product to stakeholders and potential funding sources

VETERANS BENEFIT ADMINISTRATION (VBA) · Veterans Service Representative (VSR) · Chicago, IL

Sep 2019 - Aug 2022

- Served as the Homeless Veterans Claims Coordinator (HVCC), coordinating care and paperwork for homeless veterans to expedite benefit awards resulting in a 30-90% reduction in wait time
- Determined compensation eligibility by requesting, analyzing, and developing medical evidence

GREENHEART EXCHANGE · Program Assistant · Chicago, IL

May - Aug 2019

- Directly and indirectly supported J-1 visa participants in navigating work, travel, and housing concerns by ensuring their health, welfare, and safety during their program
- Generated daily and weekly reports via database systems to support program management

PEACE CORPS (PC) TOGO Reforestation Monitoring and Evaluation (M&E) Specialist · Togo, W. Africa

Jun 2015 - Sep 2018

- Trained and supervised a team of four Togolese and four PC Volunteers to conduct long term assessment of reforestation initiatives in rural Togo, conducted 41 site visits throughout the country, and generated a comprehensive outcomes report to redesign PC Togo's agroforestry program
- Conducted comprehensive on-site needs assessment. In response trained, and coordinated a team of Togolese volunteers to cofacilitate 89 community trainings across five (5) villages for 663 adults and youth in reforestation, sustainable agriculture, nutrition, and environmental stewardship.

TOD'S CAFÉ Assistant Manager

Jan 2012 – Apr 2015

- Managed inventory, ordering, scheduling, and pricing for a café bakery that served 350 clients daily, grossing over \$300,000 annually
- Directed daily product delivery between sister restaurants, processed customers' special requests, and fulfilled catering orders
- Onboarded, trained, supervised, and managed staff meetings for five personnel

EDUCATION

App Academy · Full Stack Web Development

Graduated July 2023

- JS, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, Git, SQLite3, Express, SQLAlchemy, Flask, React, Git, AWS, Node is
- MacOS X Unix systems, TCP/IP, Security

DePaul University · Chicago, IL

Graduated August 2022

Master of Science in Public Policy

University of North Carolina Asheville · Asheville, NC

Graduated May 2013

- Bachelor of Science in Biology
- Bachelor of Arts in French

PERSONAL SOFTWARE PROJECT EXPERIENCE

SOIL MATES · Python · Flask · SQLAlchemy · React · Git · CSS · Mapbox	GitHub Repo · Live Site
 Employed Mapbox API with International Soil Research Information Center (ISRIC) API so soil data for that location, allowing for simple data retrieval without the need for knowing cool Implemented posting, commenting, and voting features which allow for users to share soil data Stack Overflow Utilized React Redux to manage state and normalize data, providing for smooth scaling into la Implemented AWS functionality to provide user with optional profile picture and to allow the 	rdinates a and information similar to arger traffic and data sets
EVERY NOTE · Python · Flask · SQLAlchemy · React · Git · CSS ☐ Managed git pull requests and merge conflicts in amicable group setting to create a clone of E ☐ Implemented Flask database backend and React front end to provide users with a note-taking and tags as well as a tasks keeper to reinforce user organization ☐ In combination with React-Redux store, organized components in a way to provide snappy res CRUD functionality.	function organized by notebooks
FAIR BNB · JS · Express · React · Git · CSS □ Created clone of Airbnb with an emphasis on modal use as a means to expedite functionality □ Implemented Express backend with React-redux front end to provide quick response times for □ Created rating system which dynamically responded to base calculations □ Employed AWS as a means for storing spot photos to provide longer-term data stability	GitHub Repo • Live Site • user